<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE pkgmetadata SYSTEM "http://www.gentoo.org/dtd/metadata.dtd">
<pkgmetadata>
	<maintainer type="person">
		<email>ilja.sara@kahvipannu.com</email>
		<name>Ilja Sara (Zucca)</name>
	</maintainer>
	<use>
		<flag name="opengl">Also build, optional, user selectable, OpenGL renderer</flag>
		<flag name="fluidsynth">Use fluidsynth as midi backend</flag>
		<flag name="portmidi">Use portmidi as midi backend</flag>
		<flag name="png">Support for (png) screenshots</flag>
		<flag name="hi-res">Support for high-resolution textures on OpenGL -mode</flag>
		<flag name="midi">Support for midi playback</flag>
		<flag name="multiplayer">Support for network play</flag>
	</use>
	<longdescription>PrBoom+ is a Doom source port developed from the original PrBoom project by Andrey Budko (Андрей Будько).

	PrBoom+ is based on the PrBoom 2.5.x line of development. It can currently be compiled in POSIX, Windows and Mac OS X environments. The current version is 2.5.1.4, released on 2016-01-10. The project saw its first developments in 2004, starting off as an unnamed PrBoom modification, but after gaining numerous additions over PrBoom it eventually adopted the separate PrBoom+ title in 2005.

In addition to all PrBoom features, PrBoom+ offers

	Chasecam for demo playbacks
	Changing the speed of the game in-game (for demo playback, recoding TAS demos, and for just playing at different speed)
	Automatic loading of WADs necessary for playback, chosen by demo name or by information present in demo file (if recorded with PrBoom+)
	Accurate Doom v1.2 emulation if needed during demo playback or requested by user
	Support for DeePBSP and ZDBSP extended nodes
	Support for the MUSINFO lump shared with Risen3D, ZDoom and GZDoom
	MIDI output with OPL emulation, FluidSynth, PortMidi, or SDL
	Ogg Vorbis and MP3 playback
	Speed optimisations for very large levels, compared to PrBoom
	Customizable HUD with the -PRBHUD- lump
	Video capture with the -viddump parameter (requires external programs)
	Support for jumping when not recording demos</longdescription>
</pkgmetadata>
